Siddhant Panda () Featured

Software Engineer seeking assignments in Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis, JSP, Log4j, Java, JAX-RPC, Hibernate, JAX-WS, JDBC, Spring, Maven, JUnit, JDBC, J2EE



Current Designation: Software Engineer Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 4 Month(s)

Current Company: Adiwebtech Solutions Pvt Ltd. Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis, JSP, Log4j, Java, JAX-

RPC, Hibernate, JAX-WS, JDBC, Spring, Maven, JUnit, JDBC, J2EE

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

Having 3+ years of design/development experience in various Java/J2EE technologies and frameworks.

Good foundation in software programming concepts of OOP's, Collection & Exceptions.

Experience includes application development using Server side technologies like JDBC, Servlets and JSP Programming.

Experienced in developing interactive web applications using Spring IOC, Spring ORM, Spring MVC, Spring AOP, Spring JDBC, Spring REST, Spring Boot.

Experienced in using ORM technologies like Hibernate.

Experienced in Distributed Technology like WebServices and Restful Services.

Strong knowledge on CoreDesign Patterns (Singleton, Strategic, Factory, Adapter, Decorator) and J2EE Design Patterns (MVC, Cache, DAO, DTO, BO, VO).

Experience in configuring and deploying application in Tomcat 6/7 and Web Logic 10.3.2Servers.

Experience in developing enterprise applications using IDE like Eclipse IDE .

Experience in using the tools like SVN, Log4j, jUnit.

Work Experience

Adiwebtech Solutions Pvt Ltd. as Software Engineer

Apr 2017 to Till Date

Project Title: Healthcare Insurance - Pacific Life

Client : Pacific Life

Environment : JSP, Spring, Java Script, Spring, Hibernate, XML

Tools Used: Junit, Log4j, Git, Eclipse.

Database : Oracle10g Individual Role : Developer

Duration : September 2019 to Till Date

Team Size : 8

Description:

Health disease management services are utilised by various commercial insurers as well as government agencies to improve their patient's health and outcomes - and thereby reducing the patient's hospitalization and medication claims. Health is leading provider of Disease Management Systems. This application works by entering a study group of patients into the database and tracking a variety of data points including general health as well as specific data pertaining to their disease. These data points are captured over many years. By analyzing these data, Health Management is able to more

1/22/2021

accurately predict a patient's likelihood of recurrence, re-admission to a hospital etc. These events would be costly to the insurance provider.

Responsibilities:

Implementing Spring MVC with Hibernate as persistence.

Configured Spring Container to implement IOC/DI of the Spring Beans and to Manage the Bean Life Cycle. Implemented Design Pattern like Singleton, Factory Design Pattern

Project #2

Project Title : Vehicle Management System(VMS)

Client : I-Go Car Sharing

Environment : Java, Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate.

Tools Used: Tortoise SVN, JIRA, Eclipse

Database : Oracle10g Individual Role : Developer

Duration : April 2018 to September 2019

Team Size : 10

Description:

VMETS is Field Service Department's most Comprehensive Web-based Vehicle Management and Expense Tracking System. VMETS provides a powerful set of modules to manage the Field Service department's Vehicle data, Vehicle's Expenses, Vehicle Trip Logs and employee expense Claims and much more. The Vehicle Management System (VMS) is the Proactive management science of using and maintaining a fleet of vehicles in such a fashion that whilst spending the minimum amount of money, a Vehicle manager is able to offer his/her users maximum flexibility, availability and reliability. VMS has been developed in conjunction with the Transport Industry in an effort to provide a total web-based solution for Maintenance, Operational and Administrative Controls in any vehicle situation.

The competitive nature of our transport world today requires that we manage all aspects of the transport business. The VMS includes customers resources, the vehicles that play an integral part in delivering your products and services to the customer.

Responsibilities:

Involved in understanding and analyzing the requirements, and development of various modules.

Implemented auditing i.e. tracking user information in admin module.

Specialized in developing web applications using leading edge technologies and frameworks such as Spring and Hibernate.

Implemented various design patterns in the project such as Strategic, Cache, MVC, Business Delegate, Data Access Object, BO, VO, DTO, Value List Handler, Service Locator, Session facade.

Participated in integrating Spring with Hibernate to make the project completely Spring Project.

Implemented the application using Spring Framework which is based on Model View Controller design pattern.

Suggestion related to performance improvements..

Getting involved in design discussions.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Biju Patnaik University of Technology in 2013

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Windows JAVA HTML, CSS, XML	
Oracle 10g, JDBC, Servlets, JSP	
Spring, Hibernate, Eclipse,Sql Developer	
Web Services (jax-rpc, jax-ws)	
Restful (jax-rs2.0)	
Weblogic10.3.2, Jboss 7.1	
Tomcat 6.0/7.0 SVN Maven JUnit	
LOG4J	

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary